mortgageloan.com 2019-01-18

# Privacy Policy | MortgageLoan.com

Last updated: July 26, 2016

Thank you for visiting [Mortgage Loan](https://www.mortgageloan.com/) Directory and Information LLC's ("Mortgageloan.com") forge Internet website located at the URL [https//www.mortgageloan.com](https://www.mortgageloan.com/) ("Site"). This Privacy Policy details certain policies implemented throughout Mortgageloan.com governing Mortgageloan.com's use of personally identifiable information about users of our Site and users of services available through this Site (the “Services”).

### Privacy Policy Updates

Due to the Internet's rapidly evolving nature, Mortgageloan.com may need to update this Privacy Policy from time to time. If so, Mortgageloan.com will post its updated Privacy Policy on our Site located at [www.mortgageloan.com](https://www.mortgageloan.com/) and we may send registered users an email, so you are always aware of what personally identifiable information we may collect and how we may use this information. If any modification is unacceptable to you, you shall cease using this Site and the Services. If you do not cease using this Site and the Services, you will be deemed to have accepted the change.

### Information Collection and Use

You can generally visit our Site without revealing any personally identifiable information about yourself. However, in certain sections of this Site and when you use our Services, we may invite you to contact us with questions or comments, request quotes or information, post content and other materials, participate in a user forum or blog, or complete a registration form. Due to the nature of some of these activities, we may collect personally identifiable information that you submit such as your name, contact data (address, email address, phone number), gender, social security number, driver’s license number, income level and other financial information, license information, username, password, age or date of birth and employment information. We may also collect additional personally identifiable information that you voluntarily include in your postings or transmit with your communications to us. Other users will be able to view who has posted certain content or documents.

We may use your personally identifiable information to deliver requested services or information, provide you, or have our third-party service partners (as described in the Disclosure Section below) provide you, with notices regarding goods or services you may be interested in purchasing in the future, register you to use our Site and Services, verify your authority to enter our Site and to improve the content and general administration of the Site and our Services.

### Method of Information Collection

Once you land on the Site and are interested in exploring obtaining a mortgage, you will find a form that you may choose to fill in.  The information consists of information concerning the value of the mortgage and the value of the security to be offered, employment status and whether you are the subject of bankruptcy and/or foreclosure proceedings and, finally, on the last page, personal details such as name and contact details. Accordingly, the completion of the form involves four (4) distinct and separate phases or stages.  After each and every stage, you are required to press a ‘Continue’ button and thereby express your willingness to continue.  At all stages you are informed that ‘SecureRights collects and transfers your information to complete your request’ and the users are given access to SecureRights policy via a link. At the end of stage 4, you are informed that by pressing on the ‘click to see your results’ button you are authorizing Secure Rights to share the information that you have voluntarily given: ‘By clicking the button above, you acknowledge, consent and agree to the following: a) Our [Privacy Policy](http://www.securerights.org/privacy.html) and consent to receive notices and other [communications electronically](http://www.securerights.org/electroniccommunications.html). b) We take your privacy seriously. You are providing express written consent for Secure Rights to share your information with up to four (4) of its [Premier Partners](http://www.securerights.org/networkmembers.html) and for Secure Rights, parties calling on behalf of Secure Rights, Premier Partners or authorized third parties on their behalf to contact you (including through automated means; e.g. autodialing, text and pre-recorded messaging) via telephone, mobile device (including SMS and MMS) and/or email, even if your telephone number is currently listed on any state, federal, local or corporate Do Not Call list. c) Consent is not required in order to purchase goods and services from the Lenders that contact you or to utilize Secure Rights services. You may choose to speak with an individual service provider by dialing (888) 883-2062. d) That I have received and reviewed the [Mortgage Broker Disclosures](http://securerights.org/licenses.html) for my state. Secure Rights NMLS 3175’.

 **If you do not want US to** collect personally identifiable information AS EXPLAINED  ABOVE **, then you should not PRESS THE ‘CONTINUE’ and/OR ‘CLICK TO SEE YOUR RESULTS’ BUTTON.**

#### Children's Privacy

Mortgageloan.com recognizes the privacy interests of children and we encourage parents and guardians to take an active role in their children's online activities and interests. This Site is not intended for children under the age of 13. Mortgageloan.com does not target its Services or this Site to children under 13. Mortgageloan.com does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13.

#### Cookies

We may use small text files called cookies to improve overall Site experience. A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's hard drive containing information about the user. Cookies generally do not permit us to personally identify you.

#### Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs)

We employ [or our third party advertising partner employs] a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We tie [do not tie] the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers’ personally identifiable information.

#### Aggregate Information

The Site may track the total number of visitors to our Site, the number of visitors to each page of our Site, browser type, and IP addresses, and we may analyse this data for trends and statistics in the aggregate, but such information will be maintained, used and disclosed in aggregate form only and it will not contain personally identifiable information. We may use such aggregate information to analyze trends, administer the Site, track users' movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use.

### Disclosure

We may provide your personally identifiable information and the data generated by cookies and the aggregate information to the vendors and service agencies that we may engage to assist us in providing our Services to you. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us. We may disclose your personally identifiable information and your communications on this Site when we reasonably believe we are required to do so by law, or when we deem it appropriate or necessary to provide such information to law enforcement authorities. We will not sell your personally identifiable information to any company or organization except we may transfer your personally identifiable information to a successor entity upon a merger, consolidation or other corporate reorganization in which Mortgageloan.com participates or to a purchaser of all or substantially all of Mortgageloan.com's assets to which this Site relates. You will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personally identifiable information. When you request a quote, make an inquiry about a loan or certain other mortgage information on this Site, you are expressly choosing to, and opting-in to, have Mortgageloan.com transfer your personally identifiable information to our third party service partners, such as SecureRights, and for such third party service partners to provide your personally identifiable information to other businesses who provide financial products or services (such as loans and mortgages) that match your inquiry. For more information, please see SecureRights’ privacy policy located at [http://www.securerights.org](http://www.securerights.org/). The third party service partners may contact you regarding your inquiry and financial products and services, but Mortgageloan.com will not contact you to offer you a loan or mortgage as further explained in our [Fraud Information page](https://www.mortgageloan.com/fraud-information).

As stated above, we may share your information with third party service partners when you use our services to request a quote or make an inquiry about a loan or certain other mortgage information on this Site (a "Request").  **In the event that you submit a Request, third party service providers may contact you directly with quotes via mail, telephone, text message, fax, email and other means of communication. You understand and acknowledge that you may receive telemarketing calls as a consequence of submitting a Request even if you are on the national ‘Do Not Call’ Registry or on any other do-not-call registry.**

If you are matched with third party service partners, you expressly consent to such third party service partners conducting any research necessary to provide you with quotes for your Request. Such third party service partners may need to share your information to conduct such research.

 **If you do not want** third party service partners **to conduct the necessary research to provide you with a quote for your Request, then you should not submit a Request.**

 **Please note that if you submit a Request through our Services and we share your information as described above in connection with your Request, you will NOT have the opportunity to opt out of the disclosure of your information in connection with that Request.**

 **If you do not want your information shared as described above, then you should not provide us with your information.**

###  **Disclaimer**

Please note that no method of transmission or method of electronic storage is fully (100%) secure.  We cannot guarantee absolute security. Therefore, notwithstanding anything to the contrary, you use our Services at your own risk and we do not promise or guarantee, and you should not expect, that your information will always remain private. In the event that an unauthorized third party compromises our security measures, we will not be responsible for any damages directly or indirectly caused by an unauthorized third party's ability to view, use or disseminate your information.

###  **Information You Disclose to Third Parties**

You may be presented with an opportunity to receive information and/or marketing offers from third parties in connection with our Services. All information you disclose to such third parties will be subject to the privacy policy and practices of such third parties. We are not responsible for the privacy policies and practices of such third parties and, therefore, you should review the privacy policies and practices of such third parties prior to disclosing information to them. If you later decide that you no longer want to receive communications from a third party, you will need to contact that third party directly.

#### Links to Third Party Sites

The Site may provide links to other Web sites or resources over which Mortgageloan.com does not have control ("External Web Sites"). Such links do not constitute an endorsement by Mortgageloan.com of those External Web Sites. You acknowledge that Mortgageloan.com is providing these links to you only as a convenience, and further agree that Mortgageloan.com is not responsible for the content of such External Web Sites. Your use of External Web Sites is subject to the terms of use and privacy policies located on the linked to External Web Sites.

#### Sharing with Friends

In the event that the Services contain any functionality allowing you to send content to a friend, then please be aware that: (a) we may display your email address to your friend; and (b) we may use information you provide about your friend to facilitate the communication and as otherwise set forth in this Privacy Policy. We do not store your friend’s email address in our database. Your friend will receive a one-time message notifying them of the shared content.

#### Security

We may employ procedural and technological security measures that are reasonably designed to help protect your personally identifiable information from loss, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction. Mortgageloan.com may use secure socket layer and other security measures to help prevent unauthorized access to your personally identifiable information.

Additionally, Mortgageloan.com’s web servers support the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) transaction in order to keep the information passed back and forth between a web server and its users confidential.

#### Data Retention

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at [/contact](https://www.mortgageloan.com/about-us#contact). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

#### Users Outside of the United States

Some of our computer systems are currently based in the United States, so your personal data will be processed by us in the United States where data protection and privacy regulations may not offer the same level of protection as in other parts of the world, such as the European Union. As a visitor from outside the United States, by using the Site you agree to this Privacy Policy and you consent to the transfer of all such information to the United States, which may not offer an equivalent level of protection of that required in the European Union or certain other countries, and to the processing of that information as described in this Privacy Policy.

#### Correction/Updating Personally Identifiable Information

Mortgageloan.com provides you with the ability to review, correct and delete any of your contact information. If you wish to review or correct any contact information you have provided to us, you may access your account online or you may contact us through our contact form. If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy please contact us through our contact form or by phone at 646 727 4845.

####  **Special Notification for California Residents -- Your California Privacy Rights**

Individuals who are residents of California and have provided their personally identifiable information to us may request information regarding our disclosures if any, of their personally identifiable information to third parties for direct marketing purposes. Such requests must be submitted to us at [webmaster@mortgageloan.com](mailto:webmaster@mortgageloan.com) or in writing at:

Mortgage Loan Directory & Information LLC

114, 5th Floor, The Strand,

Gzira GZR 1027

Malta.

California privacy rights requests must include the reference "Request for California Privacy Information" on the subject line and in the body of the message and must include the email address or mailing address, as applicable, for us to send our response. This request may be made no more than once per calendar year. We reserve the right not to respond to requests submitted other than to the address specified above.
